《僵尸國度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
我們去和大隊會合
We're gonna meet up with the team.
送摩菲到實驗室去
We're gonna get Murphy to that lab.
然后找到治愈僵尸病毒的方法
And then we are going to cure this virus.
那是個謊話  而且這謊話會害死我們的
It's a lie, and it's gonna get us both killed.
那我也情愿因相信這個謊話而死
Well then I'd rather die believing in a lie
總好過沒有信仰地茍且活著
than live believing in nothing.
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪
Addy! Addy! Addy!
堅持住  艾迪
Stay with me, Addy!
-發生什么了  -我知道那些閃回是怎么回事了
- What happened?  - I know what the flashbacks are.
我殺了我媽媽
I killed my mom.
我們誰也不會丟下其他人不管
We don't leave each other behind.
我是為你而回  我以后也會這樣做
I came back for you. I'll always come back for you.
你確定市民Z讓我們下到這里來嗎
Are you sure Citizen Z said we should be down here?
是啊  他是這么說的
Yeah, that's what he said.
聽到了嗎
Hear that?
你怎么看
What do you think, huh?
是死是活  是人還是喪尸
Dead? Alive? Human? Zombie?
死人一個
Dead.
這邊  這邊  這邊  這邊
Here, here, here, here, here.
逮到你們了
Bingo.
歌詞改編自一段美國跳長繩時唱的童謠
灰姑娘穿上了一身黃
Cinderella dressed in yella.
走到了樓上去親暖男
Went upstairs to kiss a fella.
她嗑完了藥
She took a pill.
又丟了節操
Lost her frills.
快來數數她宰了
How many zombies
幾只喪尸
does she kill?
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
你就不能給他們個痛快嗎
You couldn't just give them mercy?
那還有什么意思
What fun would that be?
那是什么
What was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
去看看
Come on.
噓
Shhhh.
站在那別動
Hold it right there.
哦  原來是奇葩二人組啊
Oh, it's the damn wonder twins.
伙計們
Guys.
搞毛線啊
What?
原來是奇葩...
The wonder...
嘿
Hey!
天吶
Oh my!
哥從來  我是說真的  一百萬年做夢也想不到
Never, I mean never, ever, in a million years,
還有機會能再看到你們
truly did I think I'd see you guys again.
市民Z讓你們到這的嗎
Citizen Z send you guys?
是啊  他說這有食物
Yeah. He told us there was food and
還說有個叫切斯特的人能幫我們逃出去
somebody named Chester who could help us out.
是啊他也這么跟我們說了  真懷疑有沒有這么個人
Yeah, he told us that too. We're starting to have our doubts.
好吧  這個人應該能幫得上忙  我們先往那邊走
Okay, well he should be, you know what, right down there.
出發吧
Let's hit it.
她怎么了這是
What happened to her?
她之前被一個帶刺的鐵絲網傷到了
She got caught on a piece of barbed wire.
現在傷口都感染了
Now it's all infected.
有人嗎
Hello!
看來我們找到切斯特了
Well I guess we found Chester.
你好啊  切斯特
Hello, Chester.
看來有人在末世過得不是很開心哦
Somebody got up on the wrong side of the apocalypse.
國 度
第一季 第十集
僵 尸
國 度
.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
你們倆在外面的時候都發生了什么
What happened to you guys out there?
翻譯 米小勒   kiko   Marshal同學  CS小明漫畫家   lottie  章魚
她弄明白了一些事情
She's working out some stuff.
你也知道  有些事情在腦海中就是揮之不去
You know how things can catch up with you.
切斯特
Chester?
你找到他們了嗎  找到我的小隊了嗎
You got them yet? You got my team?
翻譯 我叫魏碧慧   蔡茸茸   S很愛笑   迷失仁慈姐妹會   小奶
有人嗎
Hello? Anyone?
時間軸   SumenQ   安妮   太太樂嘰嘰     后期   阿小小海
是沃倫嗎
Warren?
艾迪  這真是...
Addy, it's...
看上面
Hey, hey, hey! Up here!
是你們的老朋友市民Z
It's your old pal, Citizen Z.
校對   米小勒       總監   米小勒
大家都在呀
Oh, it's everyone.
大家好
Hi, everyone. Hi!
艾迪還是一如既往那么美艷
Addy, looking gorgeous as always.
你一定就是麥克了
Oh, hey uh, you must be Mack.
呵呵  我原本以為你個子會再高一點呢
Kinda thought you'd be taller.
你這么乳臭未干也真是出乎我意料
I thought you'd be old enough to shave.
摩菲  上前頭來讓我看清楚你
Hey, Murphy. Squeeze in so I can see you.
你看起來不錯  先生
Yeah, lookin' good, sir.
你們猜怎么著  我這里有個好消息
So guess what? I've got good news.
加利福尼亞重新上線了
California's back.
大部分都還活著也連上網了
They're alive and online, well most of them.
他們準備好迎接你們了
But they're getting ready for you,
研發疫苗之夢沒有破滅
and the dream is alive.
任務繼續  衷心感謝你們
The mission is a go, thanks to yours truly.
這消息不錯是吧
That's good news, right?
好消息應該是有一包奧利奧
Good news would be a package of Oreos
和幾加侖的牛奶
and a couple gallons of milk.
沒錯  抱歉
Oh, oh yeah, right. Sorry.
在這個大廳下面左手邊的那個房間里
Down the same hall, next door on your left.
里面應該有你們需要的所有東西
Should be everything that you need.
能再次見到你們我真是太高興了
I can't tell you how good it is to see you all again.
我也很高興你能見到我們還活著  孩子
Good to see us too, kid.
這里到底是哪里
Hey, what was this place anyway?
中情局黑牢
CIA black site.
像是水刑和《獵殺本·拉登》里那樣的黑牢嗎
Oh, like waterboarding, Zero Dark Thirty, black site?
是的  是切斯特告訴我的
Yeah, I kinda thought it would be obvious
我還以為挺明顯的
from what Chester told me.
那個老家伙在哪里
So where is the old crackpot anyway?
天吶  真不幸
Oh man. Bummer.
沃倫  這段路開慢點好嗎
Whoa, Warren. Slow up here, will ya?
一個孩子而已
It's just a kid.
這可不是孩子  這是個被碾到的僵尸
That is not a kid. It's zombie road kill.
距鹽湖城251英里
十點鐘方向
Ten o'clock.
又來一個孩子
Another kid.
早就不是了
Not anymore.
停車
Stop.
沃倫停車  只是個孩子而已  停車
Warren, stop. It's just a boy. Stop.
別  你弄疼我了  別
Don't! You're hurting me! Don't!
艾迪
Addy!
干嘛
What?!
該哪哪去
Fine!
小心  前面這孩子還活著
Heads up, we got a live one.
又是個穿著古怪花襯衫一臉悲傷的孩子
Another sad kid in a weird flowered shirt.
我來對付這個
I got this one.
你還好嗎
You okay?
就是有點口渴
A little thirsty is all.
應該的
Of course.
稍等
Hold on.
給我水壺
Water.
謝了
Thanks.
喝吧孩子
Here you go, champ.
謝謝你  女士
Thanks, ma'am.
你可以叫我羅伯塔
You can call me Roberta.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫山姆
I'm Sam.
山姆
Sam.
你媽知道你自己一個人在外嗎
Does your mom know you're out here all by yourself?
我要去鹽湖城看我爸
I'm going to Salt Lake City to see my dad.
這可不是個好主意
That's not a good idea.
不  不對
Yes, it is.
我已經長大了  我終于可以見我爸了
I'm old enough now. I finally get to meet my dad.
路太遠了  況且路上也不安全
It's too far. It's not safe.
路不算遠
It's not too far.
布納恩和達克斯已經到那里了
Brennan and Dax are already there.
山姆
Sam.
鹽湖城已經被僵尸占領了
Salt Lake City's been overrun by zombies.
是哦  我知道了
Yeah, right.
等等  山姆
Uh, wait, wait, Sam.
你說的沒錯
You're right.
你已經長大了  可以去見你的父親了
You are old enough to go see your dad.
但是還有個事
But here's the thing.
我們的食物吃光了
We've run out of food.
你能幫幫我們嗎
Can you help us?
我的朋友海倫可以幫到你們
My friend Helen could help you get some food.
很好
Cool.
你能告訴我們他們住在哪里嗎
Will you show us where they live?
這樣吧
Tell you what.
你帶我們去找你朋友
You take us there,
我們開車帶你去鹽湖城
we will drive you to Salt Lake City.
好吧
Okay.
摩菲  讓個地方
Murphy, move.
你好
Hey there.
你好  小伙子  我叫麥克
Hey man, I'm Mack.
蒙蒂塞洛  猶他州
就在那邊
Just up there.
有人在家嗎
Anybody home?
非請莫入
看著好像沒人
Doesn't look like it.
麥克  你先下去偵查一下
Mack, you want to check it out?
好的
Yeah.
回到車里去
Get back in the truck!
這里不歡迎你
You're not welcome here!
慢著  別激動
Hold on, hold on!
沒事的
It's okay.
我們毫無惡意  我們只是...
We're friendly. We just...
停停停  別開火  先聽我把話說完好嗎
Stop! Stop! It's fine! Just listen to me for a second!
我們有
We have...
我記得你說她們很友善  山姆
I thought you said they were friendly, Sam.
別開火  求你們別開槍
Stop! Don't shoot! Please!
你們的孩子在我們車上
We have your boy!
山姆跟我們在一起
We have Sam!
停火
Hold your fire!
打開大門
Open the gate.
海倫女士  沒事的  他們只是想找些食物
Ms. Helen, it's okay. They just need food.
他們人不錯
They're nice.
很高興見到你  山姆
It's good to see you, Sam.
你進去找你媽吧
Why don't you go inside and find your mother?
我相信她現在急著想見你
I'm sure she's anxious to see you.
謝謝你們能帶他回來
Thank you for bringing him back.
有時我們的孩子得了幽居病
Sometimes our kids get cabin fever
然后決定要外出探險
and decide to go exploring.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
傷口感染了
It's infected.
那可能很危險
Oh, that could be dangerous.
確實
Yeah, it could.
我們可以幫助你
We can help you.
你們現在到了仁慈姐妹會
You've arrived at the Sisters of Mercy.
大姐  我們趕時間呢
Anytime now!
你不想留下也可以
You don't have to stay!
他必須得留下
Yes, he does.
我們是伙伴
We're a team.
是嗎
You are?
是的
Yes.
不管是不是伙伴
Well, team or not,
如果你想留下  你們就必須分開
if you want to stay here, you'll have to split up.
這里只讓女人和孩子進
Women and children only here.
你和你的朋友可以進
You can go inside with your friend.
但男人們必須待在墻外
But your men will have to stay outside the wall.
我們給你們二十四小時
We'll give you 24 hours.
你們可以休息  吃東西  然后上路
You can rest, get some food, and then you'll leave us.
你的想法合情合理
That's very fair of you.
請問你怎么稱呼
And you are?
海倫  你呢
Helen. And you?
羅伯塔·沃倫中尉  密蘇里國民警衛隊的
Lieutenant Roberta Warren. Missouri National Guard.
艾迪
Addy.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我會照顧她的
I got her.
沒錯  這糟透了
Yeah, this blows.
你能幫她嗎
Can you help her?
她的腿感染了  帶他去醫務室
She has an infected leg. Take her to the infirmary.
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
你好
Hi.
想看看我的胡蘿卜嗎
Want to see my carrots?
當然
Sure.
是我自己種的
I planted them myself.
在這嗎
Here?
對
Yep.
這里真美
It's beautiful here.
來吧
Come on.
我幫你
Here you go.
謝謝
Thanks.
看這個  看這里面所有的花
Now look at this one, and look at all the flowers in it.
在這里  我們自己種蔬菜
Here we grow our own vegetables.
后面我們還有雞和牛
We have chickens and cows out back.
牛  你們有牛奶嗎
Cows? You get milk?
牛奶  黃油  酸奶
Milk, butter, yogurt.
對你們來說最重要的是青霉素
Most importantly for you, penicillin.
是艾米自己做的  她以前是藥劑師
Amy makes it herself. She used to be a chemist.
廚房的琳娜
Lina's in the kitchen,
會告訴你們  哪里可以清潔一下自己
she'll show you where you can wash up.
另外  我希望你能一起來吃午餐
And I hope you'll join us for our mid-day meal.
謝謝你
Thank you.
謝謝
錯了  應該是  手背  手掌  拍
No. It's back, front, clap,
右  然后左
right, then left.
抱歉  我很久沒玩過這個了
Sorry, I haven't done this in forever.
我媽媽很久之前教過我
My mom taught me a really long time ago.
她人好嗎
Is she nice?
是的  是的  她人很好
Yeah, yeah, she is.
再來一次
Let's try again.
不管是誰建立了這個地方
Whoever built this place
他一定是預見到大災變的到來了
must've seen the Apocalypse coming.
這里簡直完美
It's perfect.
是我丈夫建立的
That was my husband.
他的處世哲學是
His philosophy was that we become
我們應該絕對地自給自足  脫離塵世
absolutely self-sufficient and off the grid.
你丈夫嗎
Your husband?
他不在了
He's gone.
像其他人一樣
Like the others.
這些女人呢
All these women?
吉娜和埃米琳是我的好姐妹
Well Zina and Emmeline were my sister wives.
亞蒙死后  我們只有彼此與這個地方
And when Ammon went, we had each other and this place.
在我們發現這些女人前  她們都很不幸
These other women weren't so lucky 'til we found them.
現在她們安全了
Now they're safe.
她們自由了
They're free.
再吃點草莓嗎
More strawberries?
不吃了   我...
No. I...
我得去找一下卡桑德拉
I think I'm gonna go look in on Cassandra
看看她怎么樣了
and see how she's doing.
-謝謝  -不客氣
- Thank you.  - Of course.
這就是你們種的胡蘿卜嗎  很好吃
So these are the carrots you grew? They're delicious.
感覺好些了嗎  謝謝你
Feeling better? Thank you.
好些了
Starting to.
還記得山姆和我們說他要去哪嗎
Remember what Sam told us about where he was going?
去鹽湖城找他爸爸
Salt Lake City to see his dad.
艾米有個比山姆大一些的兒子
Amy has a son a little older than Sam.
他現在不在這里
He's not here.
你知道為什么嗎
You know why?
他也去鹽湖城找爸爸了嗎
Went to Salt Lake City to see his dad?
女孩都在  而男孩長到13歲都離開了
The girls stay here, but all the boys leave when they turn 13.
她是這么說的
That's what she said.
她們看起來很幸福
They seem so happy.
恩  有點幸福過頭了
Yeah, maybe a little too happy.
太善良的人總會嚇到我
Nice people always scare me.
等你好起來  我們一起離開這
Let's get you well, and let's get out of here.
這里的女人讓我毛骨悚然
All these women give me the creeps.
那個金發女人一直盯著我
That blonde one keeps looking at me.
哥們  可千萬別低估了自己
Oh man, don't get down on yourself like that.
你可是一塊搶手的大肥肉
You are a perfect hunk of man meat,
你可別忘了
and don't you ever forget it.
哈哈  做好你的本分吧
Ha, ha. Don't quit your day job.
那里面真的只有女人嗎
Is there really all women in there?
是啊  小萬萬  你好好幻想一下吧
Yeah. Enjoy your imagination, kid.
你也許只能想想罷了
That's probably all you're gonna get.
多克  有一點我不能理解
You know what I don't understand, Doc?
男人都死到哪里去了
What the hell happened to all their men?
也許我們可以問問她
Well maybe we can ask her.
來自天堂的天使
Angels from heaven.
那是派嗎
Is that pie?
藍莓派  額...  我我我...我自己做的
Blueberry. Ummm, I, I, I made it by myself.
你們知道...
Do you guys know where the...
另一個人去哪了  那個...
the other one is? The one with the with the a
頭發和眼睛...  他...
the hair and those eyes? He...
一萬  別讓人打擾哥  末世結束再叫醒哥
10K, Hold my calls, wake me up after the apocalypse
我要去給他送一塊派
I'm gonna go give him a piece of this.
什么事
What?
吃派嗎
Pie?
孩子  走開
Beat it, kid.
走呀
Beat it!
你喜歡嗎
You like that?
沒關系  有人讓你受傷了嗎
It's okay. Somebody hurt you?
嗯吶嗯吶  姐了解  姐全都了解
Yeah? I know. I know.
爹地
Daddy.
你需要我的照顧
You need me to take care of you.
我想讓你停下
Part of me wants you to stop.
可是我又很想吃派
But part of me really needs the pie.
食人族嗎
Cannibals?
很抱歉你遇到了這種事
I'm so sorry that happened to you.
我真的想說我很震驚
And I wish I could say I was surprised.
天吶
Man.
他無法控制自己
He can't help himself.
動物的本能掌控了他
The animal instinct takes over.
濫殺
Kill,
破壞
destroy,
強奸
rape.
現在又是這個瘟疫  這個病毒
Now this disease, this virus.
雄性荷爾蒙才是地球上最毒的毒藥
Testosterone is the most toxic chemical on Earth.
而你挺過了這一切  來到了這里
And you survived through it all. Now you're here.
我運氣好
I was really lucky.
一開始我就遇到了麥克
I met Mack on the first night.
我看是他運氣好
I think he was the lucky one.
這是什么
What about this?
肯定有故事
This is special.
沒錯  你怎么知道的
Yeah, yeah. How'd you know?
告訴我
Tell me.
我說不出
I can't.
太沉重了
It's too much for you.
我看得出
I can see that.
你可以告訴我  告訴我吧
You can tell me. Just tell me.
是我媽媽
It was my mom.
還有我弟弟
And my brother.
我不得不...
And I had to...
兩個都是
both of them.
可憐的姑娘啊
Oh, my sweet, sweet, sweet girl.
看開吧  釋懷就好了
Let it go. Just let it all go.
我能告訴你件事嗎
Can I tell you something?
你再也不會遭遇這樣的慘劇了
You don't ever have to go through that again.
這個地方  我們姐妹
This place, our sisters,
我們會保護你的
we're protected from that.
我們用得上你這樣的姑娘
We could use a woman like you.
聰明  有本事  心地善良
Smart, resourceful, caring.
你和其他人不一樣  你很特別
You're not like the others. You're special.
我看得出
I can see that.
看來有新姐妹加入我們了
Hmmm, looks like we have a new sister.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
這位是泰莎
This is Tessa.
泰莎  歡迎你
Tessa, welcome.
你到家了
You're home now.
你安全了
You're safe.
沒事了
It's okay.
再也不會有人傷害你了
No one can hurt you here.
這就是我們存在的意義
This is why we exist.
我們建立了一個
We provide a place that is safe
不受男性暴力侵害的地方
from the violent destructive world of men.
而且我們會懲罰那些施暴者
And we bring the perpetrators to justice.
那就是我們的意義
That is our purpose.
帶上來
Bring him.
你叫什么
What is your name?
咬我啊  婊子
Bite me, Bitch.
婊子
Hmmm, Bitch.
好名字  你用著合適
I like that. It suits you.
是時候讓你見識見識正義了  婊子
Well it's time that you learn about justice, Bitch.
帶下去
Take him away.
你該來看看
You should see this.
他會有什么下場
What's gonna happen to him?
正義
Justice.
你敢傷女人  你就得死  這就是規矩
You harm a woman, you die. That's our rule.
泰莎
Tessa?
去吧  泰莎
Now, Tessa.
不
No!
他是個壞人
He was a bad man.
你還好嗎
You all right?
沒事
Yeah.
泰莎說外面還有兩個姐妹
Tessa said there are two sisters still out there.
你可以幫我們解救她們
We could use your help to free them.
當然可以
Of course.
艾迪
Addy.
你確定你要去嗎
You sure you're up to that?
沃倫
Warren.
我們都有可能像她們一樣需要幫助
Any one of us could be those sisters.
我要加入
I'm in.
好極了
Wonderful.
好吧  我也去
Yeah, you got me too.
你不必這樣
You don't have to.
沒關系
No, no, no.
我要支持我的姐妹們
I always got my sister's back.
我們得跟這些人撇清關系  小伙子們  上路吧
We got to burn this joint, boys. Time to motor.
多克  等會  大哥  怎么了
Whoa, Doc. Hold on, man. What Is it?
你看見什么了
What'd you see?
僵尸
Zombie.
熊
Bear.
有人來了
Someone's coming.
她們不會就這樣扔下我們不管了吧
They wouldn't just leave us, would they?
不可能  艾迪不會離開我的
No, Addy doesn't go anywhere without me.
對不起  伙計
Sorry, pal.
她剛才就離開你了
She just did.
他們來了
Here they come.
遇到什么麻煩了嗎  親愛的
You got a problem there, darlin'?
你覺得呢
What do you think?
你們這樣很危險啊
Kinda dangerous, ain't it?
這么漂亮的兩個姑娘
Two pretty little gals like you,
怎么能獨自上路呢
travelin' all alone?
外面可不怎么安全
It's not safe out here.
要不這樣吧
I'll tell you what.
跟我說說你們要往哪個方向走
Why don't you tell me where you're headed,
側三輪上的小伙子能幫你們檢查引擎
and Sidecar here can have a look at that engine.
手舉起來  先生們
Hands up, gentlemen.
你們的小把戲就到此結束吧
Your little game is over.
等等  別這樣  別這樣
Wait, wait, wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
我跟他們不是一伙的  他們只不過...
I'm not really with them. They just...
-我被困住了  他們把我救出來的  -閉嘴
- I was stranded, and they helped me out. - Shut up!
把槍放下
Drop your guns.
你想得美  甜心
That ain't happening, sweetheart.
別開槍  別開槍
Hold your fire! Hold your fire.
看見沒
You see, huh?
我可是個講理的人
I'm a reasonable man.
有什么事情我們可以好好商量
I'm sure we can come to some kind of an arrangement.
你直接告訴我你想要什么吧
Why don't you just tell me what you want?
我來問你
Let me ask.
這兩個女孩是自愿跟著你的嗎
These girls with you voluntarily?
恐怕不是吧
Didn't think so.
女士們
Ladies.
嘿  聽我說
Hey, hey, listen to me.
那里有個掛包  里面裝的全是奧施康定[止痛藥]
That saddlebag, it's full of oxycontin.
你可以全拿走
You can take it.
我沒興趣
Not interested.
哪有怒氣沖沖的婊子不做交易的
What kind of a raging bitch doesn't want to make a deal?
我就不
This one.
艾迪  過來幫幫忙
Hey, Addy. We could use your help over here.
伸張正義的時刻到了
It's time for some justice.
殺掉一個
Shoot one.
要致命傷  但不要爆頭
A mortal wound, anywhere but the head.
其余的人自然就解決了
The rest will take care of themselves.
不是這個
Oh, not this one.
殺另一個
The other one.
艾迪  等一下
Addy, wait.
我發誓  不是我干的  求你了  不是我
I swear. I...it wasn't me. I... please. Please. I wasn't...
真的有必要這么做嗎
Is this really necessary?
艾迪  別開槍
Addy, don't do this.
你不會想與我為敵的  好妹妹
You don't want to get in my way, sister.
求你了  我  我發誓  我什么都沒做
Please, I...I swear. I swear. I wasn't gonna do anything.
他說謊
He's lying.
記得食人族綁架了你吧
Remember the cannibal remember when he kidnapped.
還記得吧
Remember.
還記得托拜亞斯吧
Remember Tobias.
還記得他綁架了你吧
Remember when he kidnapped.
天啊  不不  不要啊
Oh, God! No! No! No!
好孩子
Good girl.
該走了
It's time to go.
我們得離開這
We got to get out of here.
我知道  我看到那頭熊了
I know. I saw the bear.
那都不算事
That's not the problem.
如果連僵尸熊都不算事了  那還有什么
If a zombie bear isn't the problem, what is?
我要見她
I need to see her.
她在一個很奇怪的地方
She's in a weird place.
我也去過那
I've been there.
將她帶出來可不是件容易的事
It's not gonna be easy to get her back.
沒關系  但是沒有她我不走
Well it's fine, but I'm not leaving here without her.
你們做好準備
You guys just get ready.
我盡全力將她帶出來
I'll do my best to get her out.
但你可能還是要做出一個選擇
But you may have a choice to make.
我知道這不容易
I know what you did seemed hard.
當我殺死自己的丈夫
I felt the same way
獲得自由的時候也有同樣的感覺
when I freed myself from my husband.
他當時也聲稱是無辜的
He said he was innocent, too.
我們從小到大
You know we were both raised to
一直堅信
believe all the rules, that
他們是好人  是真理
they were good and true and
是上帝的恩賜
from God.
在我差點死于生第五個孩子之后
And after I almost died after my fifth child,
我就開始不再相信這一切
I started not to believe.
我不想再生孩子了
I didn't want anymore children.
我不需要他了
I didn't want him.
但這些想法不符合那些信條
And that didn't square with the rules.
所以他就打我
So he beat me.
我的鼻子  胳膊還有肋骨都被他打折了
He broke my nose and my arms, ribs.
這還不算最糟的
But that's not even the worst story
這里的姐妹們還有更慘的
that you'll hear from the women in here.
我們現在就得離開
We got to go now.
你看見艾迪了嗎
You seen Addy?
沒有
No.
我們會在出去的路上找到她的
We will find her on the way out.
我會沒事的
I'll be fine.
希望如此
Hope so.
會沒事的
I will.
你是從外面進來的
You've been out there.
你知道外面是什么樣子的
You know what it's like.
我也...  不知道
I just... don't know
我應該怎么做
what I'm supposed to do anymore.
我做不到無動于衷
I can't un-see any of it.
那些人
The people,
甚至是僵尸
even the zombies.
你承受得太多了
It's too much
任何人都會這樣
for anyone.
你需要休息
You need rest.
平靜
Peace.
留在這里
Stay here.
成為我們家庭中的一員
Be a part of our family.
我不能離開麥克
I can't leave Mack.
我不能
I can't.
我愛他
I love him.
我知道你愛他  親愛的
I know you do, sweetheart.
所以讓你眼睜睜看著他死會更痛苦的
So it'll hurt all that much more when you have to watch him die.
他總有一天會死去
And one day he will die.
而你將會是那個
And it will be you
給他"施與仁慈"的人
that has to give him mercy.
是啊
Yeah.
我要怎么跟他說
How do I tell him?
我該說什么
What do I say?
我來教你怎么跟他說
I'll tell you what to say.
好的
Okay.
艾迪
Addy
能找個地方說幾句話嗎
Hey, can we go talk somewhere real quick?
好  當然可以
Uh, yeah. Yeah, of course.
里面是什么樣子
So what's it like in there?
聽上去有些怪異  畢竟一個僵尸...
Sounds a little weird, I mean a zombie...
不  不  不  麥克  里面...
Uh, no, no, no, no, no. Mack, it is...
里面很美
It's so beautiful.
要是你能看見就好了
I wish you could see it.
是啊  我也希望能看到
Yeah, I wish I could too.
跟外面的世界截然不同
It's so different from out here.
讓我有了安全感
I feel safe.
我已經很久沒有這樣的感覺了
I haven't felt that in such a long time.
不錯  很好
Good. That's good.
我很高興...
I'm glad. It's...
對你來說  離開那里應該挺難的
I'm sure it's gonna be hard to leave.
這就是我想跟你談的
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
這一切太沉重了
It's too much.
我撐不下去了  麥克
I can't do it anymore, Mack.
但是  艾迪...
But Addy...
我不能跟你一起留下來
I can't stay with you here.
我需要休息了
I need to rest.
我做不到
I can't.
沒有你  我什么都做不了
I can't do this without you.
不  不  艾迪  艾迪  拜托  拜托
No, no, no, no, no, no. Addy. Addy, come on. Come on.
我愛你  我...  你不能...
I love you. I... I... Don't you...
麥克  我真的很愛你
Mack, I love you so much.
我不能再回去  看著你死
I cannot go back out there and watch you die.
我不會死的
I'm not gonna die.
不  你會死
Yes, you will.
我們都會死
We all will.
我希望留存在我腦海里的是你現在的模樣
And this is how I want to remember you.
麥克  我不能再奪去我心愛之人的生命了
Mack, I cannot kill somebody I love ever again.
你不走  我也不會走的  艾迪
I'm not going back out there without you, Addy.
我不會  我做不到
I'm not. I can't.
這樣對大家都好
This is for the best.
艾迪  艾迪  等等  等一下
Addy. Addy, wait. Wait a minute.
摩菲怎么辦
What about Murphy, huh?
任務怎么辦
And the mission?
你說過  懷揣著信仰死去
You said, you said you would rather
總好過無所信仰地活著
die believing in something than live believing in nothing.
我得走了
I have to go.
看著我  看著我
Look at me. Look at me.
我理解  我懂  你...
I understand. I do. You're...
你媽媽的事讓你很難過  人之常情
You're upset about your mom. Of course. Of course.
這件事太可怕了  簡直是個悲劇
It's horrible. I mean it's, it's beyond horrible.
但是你會熬過去的
But you're gonna get through this.
你不是這樣的
That's not who you are.
你是個好人  你很強大
You're a good person. You're, you're, you're strong.
你很強  你不需要海倫
You're strong. You don't need Helen
還有什么腦殘邪教
and some stupid cult.
對不起
I'm sorry.
艾迪  艾迪  你不能這么做
Addy, Addy, Addy. You can't do this.
-麥克  -你不能離開我  這樣很瘋狂
- Mack. - You can't leave me. This is crazy.
-麥克  -艾迪  等下
- Mack. - Addy, wait.
-麥克  放開我  -艾迪  聽我說
- Mack, let me go. - Addy, just listen to me.
聽我說  好嗎
Just listen to me, okay?
-麥克  -你沒考慮清楚
- Mack. - You're not thinking clearly.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me!
等下  艾迪
Wait. Addy.
艾迪
Addy!
等下
Wait!
艾迪
Addy!
喂  艾迪
Hey. Addy!
艾迪
Addy!
請跟我們說話
Please talk to us!
拜托  艾迪
Come on, Addy!
也許我可以幫忙
Maybe I could help?
我想我們受夠你的幫助了
I think we've had enough of your help.
艾迪
Addy?
是我
It's me.
開門
Open the door.
艾迪
Addy?
別碰我
Don't touch me.
摩菲在哪里  我們需要帳篷
Where's Murphy? We need the tent.
他跟那個女孩還在里面
Uh, he's still in it with that girl.
她還在里面嗎
She's still in there?
派對結束了 大家要上路了
Party's over, everyone. Time to go.
你從哪里弄來香煙的
Where'd you get a cigarette?
老爹想要什么
Whatever daddy needs,
就有什么
daddy gets.
現在要上路了  親愛的
Yeah, well time to go now, sweetheart.
來吧  站起來走過去
Come on. Up and at 'em.
謝謝  老兄
Thanks, man.
否則她不會離開的
Thought she'd never leave.
驚喜吧
Surprise.
來吧  告訴她們
Go ahead. Tell them.
把你告訴我的告訴她們
Tell them what you told me.
我打定主意了
I've made up my mind.
我要跟海倫
I'm gonna stay here
留在這里
with Helen.
不行  艾迪
No. Addy.
大門出事了  我們需要你
Trouble at the gate. We need you.
你留在這里  你會沒事的
You stay here. You'll be safe.
艾迪  我知道這地方感覺很安全
Addy, I know this place feels safe.
感覺很好
It feels good.
我遇到托拜亞斯時  也是這種感覺
Well that's how I felt when I met Tobias.
但并不真實
But it wasn't real.
我和你
You and me,
一起經歷了很多
we've been through so much together.
艾迪生·卡弗
Addison Carver.
聽我說
Listen to me.
一切都夠了
Enough now.
你被卷入的這樁事兒
You got sucked into this thing,
你做出了你的努力
and you did something.
我們也都做出了努力
And we all do things.
但現在是時候離開了  現在
But it is time for us to go. Now.
我們全部
All of us.
你無需擔心
You don't have to worry.
這現在就是我的家
I'm home now.
不
No.
她怎么出來的
How'd she get outside?
她在哪
Where is she?!
那高個子呢
The tall one?
你們的頭頭呢
Your leader?
我在這  你想要什么
I'm here! What do you want?
就是你  親愛的
You, sweetheart.
我要你
I want you.
你乖乖把門打開
You open that gate
然后你乖乖出來
and you come out here.
咱們就好好聊聊
And we'll have a nice little conversation.
咱們和和氣氣的
All polite like.
殺了他
Shoot him.
我扣扳機可是出了名的快
I'm a real quick trigger.
你要是殺我
You shoot me,
她絕對跟著我一起陪葬
she's dead before I hit the ground.
五
Five.
四
Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
她會來的  是吧
She's coming, right?
當然  她會來的
Yes, she's coming.
沒事的  艾迪
It's all right, Addy.
快過來吧
Come here, please.
艾迪
Addy.
求你了
Please?
我永遠愛你  麥克
I will always love you, Mack.
咱們不來這一套
We don't do this.
咱們不能分開
We don't leave each other.
再見  麥克
Goodbye, Mack.
不
No.
你敢射他
You shot him?!
這是個警告  快給我滾
It's a warning. Get him out of here now.
趁姑奶奶們心情好
Before it gets worse.
拿上他的槍
Get his gun.
走吧
Come on.
艾迪
Addy!
-走吧  伙計  -艾迪
- Come on, buddy. - Addy!
-艾迪呢  -快走
- What about Addy? - Come on.
她不來了
She's not coming!
咱現在就走  多克
Let's go, Doc! Now!
停車
Stop the truck.
-不行  -快停車
- No. - Stop the truck!
繼續開
Keep driving!
麥克  麥克  麥克
Mack, Mack, Mack.
我不能就這么走了
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
我不能
I can't.
上車
Get in!
蝴蝶蝴蝶  無憂無慮
Butterfly, butterfly, happy all day.
蝴蝶蝴蝶  飛飛飛飛
Butterfly, butterfly, fly fly away.
三只小蝴蝶  繞著你跳舞
Three little butterflies looking at you.
一只飛走了  還剩下兩只
One flew away and then there were two.
兩只小蝴蝶  曬著日光浴
Two little butterflies soaking up the sun.
一只飛走了  只剩下一只
One flew away and then there was one.
一直小蝴蝶  終日獨徘徊
One little butterfly stayed all along.
蝴蝶飛走了  它們都走了
It flew away and then they were gone.